JOSEPH RABON

822 Jackson Circle, Fort Lee, VA 23801 • Cell: (843) 516-3406 • rabonjoseph@ymail.com

Professional Summary

Decorated service member with experience working with other countries and training with language barriers. Currently holding a secret clearance and has experience working with secret service in combat zone. Graduated from Non-commissioned officer academy as distinguished honor graduate. Vast experience overseeing security operations. Experience with air assault operations and qualified.

Skills

- Weapons training
- First Aid certified
- Secret Security Clearance
- Troubleshooting
- Organized
- Firearm and explosives handling
- Air Assault Qualified

- Trained in security
- Quick learner
- Team leader
- Trained in counterterrorism strategies
- Trained in cross-cultural communication
- Small arms qualified expert

Work History

Infantry/ Security Management, 01/2011 to Current Army National Guard – Mullins, SC

- Small arms expert
- Operated live weapons ranges
- Developed and led training programs in preparation for combat.
- Trained in the use of tear gas and explosives.
- Employed, fired and recovered anti-personnel and anti-tank mines.
- Operated and maintained communications equipment.
- Performed as a fire team member during situational training exercises and all infantry dismounted battle drills.
- Surveyed and analyzed terrain to determine optimum equipment placement and use.
- Led fire team during infantry dismounted battle drills and situational training exercises.
- Coordinated integration of company weapons systems into those of adjacent platoons.
- Tracked personnel and supplies within the company.
- Planned and briefed personnel on missions.
- Gathered evidence and processed crime scenes and evidence.

Equipment Installer, 10/2014 to 01/2015 Planet Fitness – New Hampshire

Installed fitness equipment.

Operated forklift

Server, 08/2013 to 07/2014

Outback Steakhouse - Colonial Heights, VA

Provided food service to customers

Restocked and maintained workplace

Field Maintenance, 04/2013 to 04/2014

Country Club of Virginia - Richmond, VA

Keep property presentable

Infantry/ Recon/ Management, 05/2004 to 09/2009

Active Army - US

- Graduated distinguished honor graduate of NCO academy.
- Provided reconnaissance in Afghanistan to determine composition and disposition of enemy.
- Sorted and routed incoming correspondence and messages.
- Developed and led training programs in preparation for combat.
- Employed, fired and recovered anti-personnel and anti-tank mines.

- Operated and maintained communications equipment.
- Performed as a fire team member during situational training exercises and all infantry dismounted battle drills.
- Led fire team during infantry dismounted battle drills and situational training exercises.
- Coordinated integration of company weapons systems into those of adjacent platoons.
- Tracked personnel and supplies within the company.
- Planned and briefed personnel on missions.
- Gathered evidence and processed crime scenes and evidence.
- Small arms expert

Education

Bachelor of Science: Health and Wellness, Current Ashford Universtiy - San Diego, CA